Edward A. Khairallah Papers
© 2006 University of Connecticut
- Series I: Papers, undated, 1958-1996
  - (Box 8)
    - "Effects of Leupeptin and Pepstatin on Protein Turnover in Adult Rat Hepatocytes in Primary Culture" Tanaka et al, Biochemistry and Biophysics, 1981 April
    - "Hepatic Gluconeogenic Enzymes, RNA Metabolism and Amino Acid Levels in Rats Carrying Transplantable Growth Hormone-Secreting Pituitary Tumors", Weber et al, Endocrinology, 1966 November
    - Holiday postcard, undated
    - "Hormonal Regulation of Serine Dehydratase Activity In Primary Cultures of Adult Rat Hepatocytes", Noda et al, Biochemical and Biophysical Research Communications, 1981 May
    - "Intracellular Protein Degradation in Mammalian and Bacterial Cells: Part 2," A.L. Godberg and A.C. St. John, Annual Review of Biochemistry, 1976
    - "Proteolysis in Isolated Autophagic Vacuoles From Rat Liver", Ahlberg et al, Experimental Cell Research, 1982
    - Special Seminar Series on Biochemical Regulatory Mechanisms, undated
    - Structure, Dynamics, and Biogenesis of Biomembranes, ed. Sato and Ohnishi, undated
    - "The Unification of Muscle Structure and Function: A Semicentennial Anniversary", Heinz Herrmann, Perspectives in Biology and Medicine, 1989 Autumn
    - "Acetaminophen Targeted Proteins in Isolated Nuclei, Mitochondria, and Other Subcellular Organelles From Fractionated Mouse Liver", Bulera et al, undated
    - "Glutathione Depletion, Oxidative Stress and the Regulation of Hepatic Protein Turnover,", undated
    - ("The Partial Amino Acid Sequence of the Major 58-kDa Acetaminophen Binding Protein 58-ABP Is Homologous to a Selenium Binding Protein", International Congress of Toxicology, Rome, Italy, 1992
    - "Purification, antibody production and partial amino acid sequence of the 58-kDa acetaminophen-binding liver proteins", Bartalone et al, Toxicology and Applied Pharmacology, 1992
    - Unidentified manuscript and correspondence, undated
  - (Box 9)
    - Notes from graduate seminar in psychology at Harvard, 1956
    - Amino Acid Analyzer Service, circa 1979
    - Seminar Series in conjunction with Biochemical Regulatory Mechanisms course, 1980
    - Society of Toxicology conference, 1991
    - "Acetaminophen Hepatotoxicity and Cellular Homeostasis;" "Acetaminophen Binding & Hepatocyte Homeostasis in Toxicity,", 1987-1993
    - Funding requests to UConn Research Foundation for "Why We Should Care Whether Intracellular Proteins Are Positively or Negatively Charged In Vivo,", 1983
    - Research Foundation Awards, undated
    - "Acetaminophen-Induced Hepatotoxicity: Analysis of Total Covalent Binding Versus Specific Binding to Cysteine,", undated
    - "Bartolone III TAP '89/ Bartolone B.P. 1988 II" ("Immunochemical Analysis of Acetaminophen Covalent Binding to Proteins: Partial Characterization of the Major Acetaminophen-Binding Liver Proteins", Bartolone et al, Biochemical Pharmacology, 1988; "Selective Acetaminophen Metabolite Binding to Hepatic and Extrahepatic Proteins: An in Vivo and in Vitro Analysis", Bartolone et al, Toxicology and Applied Pharmacology, 1989, 1988-1989
    - "Manuscript and Final Reprint" [of "Selective Protein Arylation by Acetaminophen and 2,6-Dimethylacetaminophen In Cultured Hepatocytes From Phenobarbital-Induced and Uninduced Mice", Birge et al, Biochemical Pharmacology], 1989
    - "Manuscript and Reprint" [of "Selective Protein Arylation and the Age Dependency of Acetaminophen Hepatotoxicity in Mice", Beierschmitt et al, Toxicology and Applied Pharmacology], 1989
    - "Paper With Bartolone" ("Immunochemical Detection of Acetaminophen-Bound Liver Proteins", Bartolone et al, Biochemical Pharmacology], 1987
    - "Paper With Ray ['The Arylation of Microsomal Membrane Proteins…'] and Correspondence", undated
    - "Paper With Ray Birge" ("The Arylation of Microsomal Membrane Proteins by Acetaminophen is Associated with the Release of a 44 kDa Acetaminophen-Binding Mouse Liver Protein Complex into the Cytosol", Birge et al, Toxicology and Applied Pharmacology, 1991
    - "Paper With [Charles] Tyson" ("Comparative Toxicity: Mechanistic Studies On Acetaminophen Action In Vitro and In Vivo in Various Species Including Man", Tyson et al), undated
    - "Paper With [Benjamin] Weeks" ("Acetaminophen Toxicity to Cultured Rat Embryos," Weeks et al, Teratogenesis, Carcinogenesis, and Mutagenesis), undated
    - "Paper #III With Ray" ("Receptive protein thiols: Selective protein arylation by acetaminophen and protein S-thiolation by glutathione", Birge et al, Biochemical Pharmacology, 1990
    - "Separation Paper from Japan" ("Sequestration of Cytoplasmic Enzymes in an Autophagic Vacuole-Lysosomal System induced by Injection of Leupeptin", Kominami et al, Journal of Biochemistry, 1982
    - "Tarloff, Joan" ("Sex- and Age-Dependent Acetaminophen Hepato- and Nephrotoxicity in Sprague-Dawley Rats: Role of Tissue Accumulation, Nonprotein Sulfhydryl Depletion, and Covalent Binding", Tarloff et al, Fundamental and Applied Toxicology), 1996
    - "Two Manuscripts and Two Reprints" [of "Acetaminophen Hepatotoxicity: Correspondence of Selective Protein Arylation in Human and Mouse Liver in Vitro, in Culture, and in Vivo", Birge et al, Toxicology and Applied Pharmacology, 1990
    - "Two Paper Drafts and One Reprint" [of Immunohistochemical Localization of Acetaminophen-Bound Liver Proteins", Bartolone et al, Fundamental and Applied Toxicology], 1989
  - (Box 10)
    - "Coordinate Regulation of Hepatic Intracellular Proteolysis With Autophagic Sequestration But Not With Cathepsin B1 Activity", Makowski and Khairallah, American Society of Biological Chemists Conference, 1981
    - "Diurnal Variation in Protein Metabolism in Livers of Meal-Fed Rats", Hundt and Khairallah, abstracts for 10th and 11th International Congress of Biochemistry and FASEB conference (numerous copies, varying titles), undated, 1980
    - "The Effect of Glucose and Inhibitors of RNA Synthesis on Hepatic Phospho-enol-pyruvate Carboxykinase" (Treadow and Khairallah), undated
    - "Effect of Protease Inhibitors on Short-term Proteolysis in Hepatocytes", Russell and Khairallah, undated
    - "In Vivo Determination of Rates of Protein Degradation in Livers of Meal-Fed Rats: Implications of Amino Acid Compartmentation", Khairallah [abstract], undated
    - "The Intracellular Amino Acid Pool Is Not the Primary Precursor For Amino-tRNA in Rat Liver", Khairallah et al, 9th International Congress of Nutrition, 1972
    - "Nutritional Evaluation of Lysime in Soy Milk and Corn Meal Fermented With L. Bulgaricus and L. Acidophilus Lysine Excreting Mutants", Hermayer et al, FASEB Conference, 1978
    - "Origin and Possible Significance of Alanine Production by Skeletal Muscle", Odessey et al, undated
    - "Regulation of Intracellular Proteolysis in Meal Fed Rats and Intralysosomal Amino Acid Compartmentation" (Khairallah, et al) - American Society of Biological Chemists conference abstract, 1978
    - "The Tryptophan Stabilization and Glucose Repression of PEPCK in Fed, Starved and Diabetic Rats" (Treadow and Khairallah), FASEB conference abstract, 1972
    - [untitled, n.a., begins] "Reliable rates of protein biosynthesis from isotopic data...", undated
    - Alan R. Liss, Inc., Scientific, Medical and Scholarly Publications, undated
    - Biochemistry 310 and 324, MCB 324 course information, circa 1976
    - Handouts (including "PFK/FDPase" and "Glycolysis, Gluconeogensis and Lipogenesis"), undated
    - Qualifying graduate exam questions, 1981 February
    - Biological Sciences Group faculty listing, 1973-1974
    - Correspondence, 1971-1990
    - Expenditures report for NIH Grant 13986-02/UConn Research Foundation grant 0202-462, 1971
    - Grant correspondence, 1971-1973
    - Project reports, 1971-1973
    - Biography/resume of Dr. E. Khairallah, 1975
    - Correspondence, undated
    - Subcellular Methodology Symposium [Wolfson Bioanalytical Centre, University of Surrey, UK] Abstracts, 1973 July
    - "Bernard Katz - On Structure and Functions of Neuromuscular Contacts - Dunham Lectures", undated
    - "Chromatography", undated
    - "Edith Bulbring - Physiology and Pharmacology of Intestinal... [illegible], undated
    - "Food Regulation", 1964 January
    - "Horizons in Regulation", undated
    - "Regulation of Food Intake", undated
    - Reprinted/photocopied publications, 1966-1980
    - Student files, undated
  - "Biochem 339", undated (Box 11)
    - "Course outlines" [MIT, UConn], 1966, 1969-1973
    - "1998 Gordon Conference on Lysosomes"
    - "Amino Acid Analyzer Course in California" [Beckman Instruments Inc.], 1968
    - "Amino Acid Analyser Service - Letter from [William C.] Orr [V.P. of Academic Affairs]", 1977
    - "Animal Care Letters", 1973-1974
    - "Fifth International Symposium on Intracellular Protein Catabolism", 1984
    - "Postdoctoral Biological Sciences - Khayambashi" (postdoctoral fellowship applications/nominations], undated
    - Application for Continuation Grant (NIH) - "Starvation and Regulation of Protein Degradation", 1974
    - Grant files, 1969-1971
    - Bulletins/pamphlets/booklets, 1969-1970
    - Department and University Matters, 1970-1988
    - "Compartmentation of Free Amino Acids in Rat Liver", Airhart et al (1 draft, 2 final drafts, 1 publication copy in Biochemical Journal), undated
    - "In Vivo Determination of Rates of Protein Degradation in Livers of Meal-Fed Rats: Implications of Amino Acid Compartmentation", Khairallah et al, undated
    - "Regulation of Enzyme Synthesis and Activity in Mammalian Liver: the Hormonal Control of Glycolysis and Gluconeogenesis", undated
    - "The Role of Hormones in the Regulation of Glycolysis and Gluconeogenesis in Rat Liver", undated
    - American Society of Biological Chemists conference abstract forms, 1976
    - "Outline of Inborn Errors of Aromatic Amino Acids", undated
    - Symposium: Recent Research in Diabetes, Intermediary and Drug Metabolism, participant directory, 1970 May
    - UConn Research Foundation grant application by Dr. Kirvin L. Know, 1972
    - UConn Research Foundation grant budgets/correspondence, 1973
    - Reprinted/photocopied publications, 1965-1983
    - "Diurnal Biuret/Lowry Assays" [Hundt], undated
    - "Diurnal Changes in Hepatic Protein Metabolism in Meal-Fed Rats [Hundt et al]", undated
    - "Cellular Aspects, Cellular Interaction and Control Processes: Compartmentation of Free Amino Acids for Protein Biosynthesis - II. Influence of Hepatic Amino Acid Concentrations on the Composition of the Precursor Pool Charging Aminoacyl-tRNA", Vidrich et al [submitted to Biochemical Journal], undated
    - "P & T" [raw data], 1977
    - "Raw Data, Never Published - Diurnal Amino Acid Patterns", undated
    - Publication files, undated, 1976
    - Student files, undated